<project name="catalog-flow"
         stack="nextjs"
         version="0.1.0"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../pxml.xsd"
         autogen-tests="true">
  
  <node id="api.products" type="api-route" flow="catalog.products">
    <meta>
      <path>app/api/products/route.ts</path>
    </meta>
    <input>
      <field name="category" type="string" required="false" />
    </input>
    <output>
      <field name="products" type="array" required="false" />
    </output>
    <constraint verify="static">Use the shared database connection imported from '@/lib/db' (or relative path) for all database operations instead of creating new Database instances. Create products table (id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY AUTOINCREMENT, name TEXT, price REAL, description TEXT, image TEXT, category TEXT, rating REAL, reviewsCount INTEGER) if not exists. Seed with 10+ items if table is empty. Support GET and POST. Ensure the route is dynamic and not cached by exporting: export const dynamic = 'force-dynamic';</constraint>
    <test>
      <name>Get products list successfully</name>
      <given>
        <query>
          <category>electronics</category>
        </query>
      </given>
      <expect>
        <status>200</status>
      </expect>
    </test>
  </node>

  <node id="ui.products" type="ui-component" flow="catalog.view">
    <meta>
      <path>app/products/page.tsx</path>
      <depends_on>api.products</depends_on>
    </meta>
    <constraint verify="static">File exports default React component</constraint>
    <constraint verify="static">Fetch the products from '/api/products' on mount</constraint>
    <constraint verify="static">If fetch request fails or returns non-ok status, stop loading state and show a clear error message in the UI.</constraint>
    <constraint verify="static" learned-from="catalog.list">Ensure the SQLite table products is seeded properly, fetch from /api/products returns a valid JSON array on client mount, and errors are handled gracefully without crashing the UI.</constraint>
    <constraint verify="llm-judge">Create a professional products catalog view at app/products/page.tsx (styled with beautiful Tailwind grid). Display them with product cards showing image, title, description, price, and an 'Add to Cart' button calling the cart addition logic via fetch POST request to '/api/cart'. Include a navbar linking to Home ('/') and Cart ('/cart').</constraint>
  </node>

</project>
